Muhammad Talha Qadir

SEECS-NUST, H-12, Islamabad, Pakistan

m.talha.qadir779@gmail.com | contact@mtqadir.me | +923070979731

mtgadir.me | github.com/mtalhagadir779| linkedin.com/in/talha-gadir

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Programmer and Cyber Security enthusiast with some hands-on experience in Google Cloud Platform, Web development and deployment using HTML, CSS, jquery, Angular, and other frameworks. I am a hard working, honest individual. I am a good timekeeper, always willing to learn new skills. An enthusiastic, self-motivated, reliable, and responsible person. Having good problem solving skills and great to work with teams and easy to get along with.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Personal Portfolio Website (https://mtqadir.me)

March 2021-Present

- Designed and planned responsive Front-End Design for Website using Bootstrap and JavaScript.
- Deployed the Website on GitHub pages to add custom domain.
- Tested the website on different platforms for compatibility and responsiveness and deployed.

Volunteer at Chadar Foundation NUST

Sep 2020-Oct-2020

- Co-Managed the Sahara project in Bahawalpur.
- Assisted in collection, packing and distribution of donated clothes and other necessities to locals in need.
- Documented and reported the process to the Foundation.

Eco-Intern at WWF-Pakistan

July 2019-Aug 2019

- Handled Social media activities.
- Provided IT support to the team.
- Developed team communications and information for meetings.

EDUCATION

School of Electrical Engineering and Computer Sciences, NUST

Bachelor of Computer Sciences

2018-2022

Rangers College, Bahawalpur

Intermediate (Pre-Engineering), A+ Grades

2016-2018

PROJECTS AND CERTIFICATES

Introduction to Cyber Security (View Certificate):

- Offered by Cisco Networking academy.
- A Basic introduction to Network and Cyber Security.

GCP Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure (View Certificate):

- Offered by Google Cloud at Couresra.org.
- Introduction to GCP platform and their core infrastructure.

Library Management System in C (View Repository):

- Provides hands on experience to all the basic programming and C language fundamentals.
- Made a Console based C application for Library management.
- Used file handling, reading, and writing algorithms and libraries to implement a structured management system.

SKILLS

- Familiar with Google Cloud Platform.
- Efficient in programming using Python and C/C++.
- Familiar with Flutter framework and dart.
- Critical Thinking and Problem Solving.
- Web Development using HTML5 CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap, PHP, MySQL.
- Configuring simple networks using software-based Cisco Network Tracer.